# HAFIZ ZAIN UL ABIDEEN

# Front End Developer / VueJS Developer

Lahore, PK 54000

xainbutt888@gmail.com

+92 311 444 3774

Graduate in Computer Science, specializing in the processes of designing and developing Professional Websites with a strong Front End experience. I'm graduated from The University of Punjab, Lahore has a deep interest in Full Stack Development and Project Management. My goal is to apply my development skills at a professional level, with a focus on efficiency and client satisfaction

#### Skills:-

- 1. HTML, CSS (SASS), JS, Jquery, Bootstrap, PHP, Vue.JS.
  - 2. PSD to HTML (Pixel Perfect)
    - 3. Cross Browser Testing
    - 4. Fully Responsiveness
      - 5. Adobe Photoshop
  - 6. Search Engine Optimization (OnPage/OffPage)
    - 7. Web Content Writing
    - 8. DNS & Hosting Tech Support

https://frontdev.ga/ Willing to relocate: Anywhere



# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Front End VueJS Developer**

BearPlex - Lahore

September 2020 to Present

Currently working on developing a project management software with Vue.js, Laravel

- Developing user-facing applications using Vue.js
- Building modular and reusable components and libraries
- Optimizing application for performance
- Implementing automated testing integrated into development and maintenance workflows
- Staying up-to-date with all recent developments in the JavaScript and Vue.js space
- Keeping an eye on security updates and issues found with Vue.js and all project dependencies
- Proposing any upgrades and updates necessary for keeping up with modern security and development best practices
- Proficiency with modern development tools, like Babel, Webpack, and Git
- Highly proficient with Vue.js and its core principles such as components, reactivity, routing, plugins (bootstrap-vue / vuetify), and the virtual DOM
- Familiarity with the Vue.js ecosystem, including Vue CLI, Vuex, Vue Router, and Vue Layouts

- Good understanding of Javascript compiling language TypeScript
- Learning & adopting Vue with Nuxt.Js

#### Front End Developer & IT Manager

MST Developers Ltd - Lahore

August 2019 to June 2020

- 1. HTML, CSS (SASS), JS, Jquery, Bootstrap, PHP.
- 2. PSD to HTML (Pixel Perfect)
- 3. Cross Browser Testing
- 4. Fully Responsiveness
- 5. Adobe Photoshop
- 6. Search Engine Optimization (OnPage/OffPage)
- 7. Web Content Writing
- 8. DNS & Hosting Tech Support

#### Front End Developer & IT Assistant

DCM DIRECT LLC (Dream Catcher Marketing) - Lahore

October 2018 to June 2019

- 1. HTML, CSS. JS, Jquery, Bootstrap
- 2. Template Customization
- 3. Google Systematic Pages
- 4. Fully Responsiveness
- 5. SEO Optimized
- 6. Front Page Exposure
- 7. Web Content Writing
- 8. DNS & Hosting Tech Support

# Web Developer Intern

MindBridge (PVT) - Lahore, PK January 2018 to October 2018



**EDUCATION** 

# **Bachelor's in Computer Science**

**University of the Punjab** - Lahore September 2014 to March 2019

# Intermediate in FSC Pre-Engineering

**Punjab Group of Colleges - Lahore** August 2012 to July 2014

# **High School in Biology**

**Cathedral High School** - Lahore May 2010 to April 2012



#### SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- SASS
- scss
- Bootstrap
- PHP
- PSD to HTML
- · Adobe Photoshop
- VS Code
- Technical Content Management
- · Tech Support
- Search Engine Optimization
- · Vue.JS (Less than 1 year)



LINKS

https://github.com/xainbutt888

https://www.facebook.com/zain.butt.14289

https://www.frontdev.ga/

https://www.instagram.com/zain\_butt\_\_\_/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hafiz-zain-48a1531ab/



#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

My name is Hafiz Zain UI Abideen. My years of experience as a Front End Developer for different multinational companies such as Dream Catcher Marketing (DCM DIRECT LLC) has honed my CSS3 and HTML5 skills, as well as my knowledge of mobile and responsive design.

My professional experience includes bringing the wireframes of the UX designer to life through HTML5 and CSS3, as well as collaborating with Back End Developers to create a stellar finished product. I think my skills and experience make me a great fit for your company.

Here are some of my most relevant qualifications and accomplishments:

Nearly one year of experience as a Front End Developer at Mindbridge PVT.

Eight months of experience as a Front End Developer for Dream Catcher Marketing (DCM DIRECT LLC)

Worked at MST Developers as Front End Developer & IT Manager.

Currently working at BearPlex on a UI framework Vue.JS

I crafted various website features using HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript Jquery and Bootstrap

Developed and Implemented project scope and timelines based on the design-develop-deploy process

Collaborated with UX designers and Back End Developers and ensured coherence between all parties

Tested feature prototypes for bugs and user experience

I know how important the details are for a Front End Developer.

My keen attention to detail and dedication to solving any problem at hand is what separates me from other candidates with similar qualifications.

If you agree that I'd be a good fit for your organization, I would love to schedule an interview at your earliest convenience.

Visit this link for Portfolio Projects & Resume

https://www.frontdev.ga/